and this is the other big issue of our
time that we don't even talk about the
Europeans try to avoid Americans and mr.
Tripp he's called abortion the irony is
that after we did Hitler in the
concentration camps installed in the
gulags and discovered the horrors of the
tyrant mmm-hmm of the boy king who
became the boy priest at the same time
three bad things once in the same person
Hitler and Stalin okay we did that in
the 1940s in Europe we learned learn us
and hopefully we don't want it back
well they'll turn ative which is to call
Hitler evil and then make everything
else good it's not sustainable either
because we arrived in as a side of
intense mediocrity mm-hmm the mediocrity
sent us all to the fact that we didn't
have God and long we had the devil okay
if you have the devil that means
everybody who's opposed to the devil is
there for good love to do whatever they
want and that's exactly ended up in this
childish infantile fairytale that any
mediocre output that we do is valued by
somebody even though it's mediocre and
what did it was throwing back at us is
that no nobody's following if you're
putting crap out there did it so because
it was flat fooled us into believing it
first this was a magical kindergarten
fantasy where everybody will be seen and
heard it was called user-generated
content in 2005 I wrote a paper so
that's just a wet fantasy from telecom
companies because they don't want to pay
for the contents it's not going to
happen yes you're gonna drown in shit
but once we ground in all this junk
we're gonna go for quality Netflix is
way more in the future than Facebook is
same thing because that is talent
generated content you find the talent
that talent writes the story the real
priests writing mythology they make a
story out of it it's called television
show bur
caustic they watch that at night instead
of scrolling on Facebook of course they
do mm-hmm talent generated content and
few people have the calling to be the
talented priestess tell to tell the
formidable story unfortunately the best
way
people don't have the time to do that
sorry but they don't an abortion then
sneaked into the picture saying it
oh sorry you're good to talk about
abortion before well yeah it's a FEMA
system in a way but I'm told it's all
right it's what you know no it's it's
just like instead of concentration camps
you killed people in abortion clinics
but you do it because you know it cannot
give birth to all the children you could
possibly have not all potentialities can
come true that's what's important to
building ethics on actualities I'm for
abortion because we do the Portia's you
tell a woman you get pregnant you want
to keep the baby unknown and what the
woman then dust herself and her sisters
she goes to metric the metric says well
you know really prepared to give birth a
child right now you could have another
child - yes or no but otherwise she
wouldn't have
and we then arrived at the beautiful
ethical principle which is that the
grown-up generation can all accept the
children then it can handle and any
civilized society based on that the
nation state borders today has to be
protected from uncontrolled migration
because you cannot let everybody in the
funny thing is to the people who defend
the nation state borders apparently are
suddenly pro-life anti-abortion they
don't even get what's going on what's
going on and is that we understand the
difference between potentiality and
actuality and not all potentiality may
happen because we don't have space for
that we don't have time for that yes the
vast majority of these will be killed
every time a sperm hits an egg half a
million potentialities are killed all
the sperms that didn't hit the egg are
dead only one sperm gets dead that
becomes an embryo that embryos to
potentially become a human being will it
be human being or not we now decide at
the first few weeks then it becomes
human being and we do all we can once
it's born to save it mm-hmm we
understand actuality I'm pro-abortion
because what the fuck will be the
alternative the alternative to force
women to give birth to children they
hate we did that before it was
disastrous
[Music]
I think the metric and the woman's I'm
totally for that a sorry if you were the
guys stick to your dick and sit inside
the womb and the babies coming up you're
gonna be held responsible for the rest
those men because you were there that
what's your ritual you did that because
enjoyed it you have to take
responsibility for it nothing else can
be on not nothing else can be ethically
acceptable today and some pro-abortion
and pro nation state borders because to
me the same thing
we cannot allow an invasion into system
that will kill that system okay and a
female body is a system that she'll be
respected as such
nation-state is the system now I see the
analogy has to work so yeah I'm gonna
write about abortion and I'm gonna say
abortion is murder murderers okay mm-hmm
we need to rework it learn stalling over
again we just we just
propertied over we didn't earn about
trying to say we're not them peterson
points that out that's one of his best
moments he points out there's a
concentration camp commander in all of
us yeah that's yeah that's that's that's
one of his best points I agree that's
that's an abortion Eastern all of us
it's also battle anti-abortionist in
Lagos and he has to go
[Music]
this is Tower of Babel without your
Buress mythology this is Grandin nurture
for the next 100 years we're talking
about here as we need to discuss a
person we need Scott is so paz'
I know that the most sensitive topics
out there are the ones that also are the
most important they just miss understood
they need to be read and then retold in
the proper way
that's deep priestly work and for me to
do that people takes retraction that's
why I'm pulling up get the distance and
start looking at from the outside why it
takes retraction because you're gonna
get stones thrown out here if you open
your mouth of course you know that's the
first thing you learn when you're that
priest you should they throw rocks at
you yeah forgive them cuz they don't
know what they're doing you know Jesus
said that whether y'all mm-hmm wasn't a
big deal okay how would they know better
you know nobody's told them or they
didn't learn mm-hmm no what subsets you
come back into the village you tell them
the same story again I said I told you
this before you didn't listen you
deserve the rocks coming down from the
sky killing it you deserve it because
you didn't listen same thing
today we'll see if the people are
listening if nothing else they learned
the hard way which is when digital it's
them life is not gonna be easy for them
millions of people made redundant yes
yeah
prepare for it did you huh and you
didn't say what you had to say you
didn't save the nation states that we
have to say because we don't have
anything else nothing else that operates
inside of us we don't like to do
politics of people who don't speak our
own language don't look like ourselves
that's what the European Union is not
working the reason why it's not working
is that there is no European scene
there's no European stage there's no
European arena there's no common
language Italians don't speak English
how Holdings gotta talk because if they
don't speak the same language well of
course they can't be the same Union they
can collaborate but he can't be in the
same Federation and India at least
everybody speaks English so they can
have a federation so India's the
successful version of the European Union
interesting and far more sustainable
than China Russian America yeah it's not
gonna be what people think it is my
never ever people think it is it's
always not my babies on the small
city-states they're firmly ruled
according to factuality I don't care if
the Democratic or have some kind of a
dictator leadership or whatever I mean
there are benevolent dictators they can
do a good job for what at least as long
as people can move they don't mind
staying to read them okay back to the
shamans back to the shamans yeah explain
the role of the shaman
okay you go back to Mesopotamia and
Egypt mm-hmm you ask yourself how are
the first cities built they weren't
villages the group cuz the villages of
fortresses
religious with 20 50 people and a wall
it's good question all right yeah
interesting question so you asked an
ecologist and they say well we've looked
at we discovered that the first thing
they built was a ritual place
shaman's the way it's original place it
means that you got the andrew village
andrew tribe settled up there upriver
and i sitting further down the river
with the other condor tribe and we
realized these tribes are gonna kill
each other to get connected with each
other
cuz they always kill each other that's
what they've done as long as they were
nomadic we can make we can't allow that
to happen just like you and i are
discussing abortion here we're
discussing you know the national the
nation of Israel and the cosmopolitan
Palestinian we discussing new solutions
to problems that people are stuck with
because they're misunderstood same thing
we need to find a new story that
connects people okay what are we gonna
do we build the cigarette we build
stairs towards the sky mm-hmm cuz we
think of the finally gates in the sky
somebody looks down on us from the sky
their father looks down on us with it
but Neverland to prefer my okay so you
walk up one side of the stairs
you tell you traveling we've celebrated
the old father Andrew in our tribe and I
woke up the other stair and I said oh we
celebrate it will father Aleksandr in
our tribe and then Andrew Alexander set
down by drawing water and we looked at
this really deeply and we discover that
actually these are just names so and
you're not excited at the same guy and
his name is God and God is on the stage
right so God arrives and Monica
summarizes it's just the ultimate or
father of all the tribes along the river
and once that stories there is only a
matter of time before one of the tribes
expands and includes the others and
creates a federation mm-hmm and when
that group becomes a bit too corrupt
lacy than the power if somewhere else
another empire expands that's all you
need a god right that's why you you need
a god that that yeah you need a god to
unite everybody yeah and it was obvious
from the very beginning that's the wrong
God goddess is the name of all our
dreams combined
projected onto one single spot yeah I
mean if personally if if I don't have a
promise that I could make to something
higher than myself I'm going to waste
my time you know drinking or something
you know yeah so so you need a higher
principle to to make cause some guys
enough to swear loyalty to the tribe
that means you you swear loyalty the
military original mayor between men
soldiers and he says that I'll take the
boat for you if I can so you can survive
I'd rather see myself die than you die
you can create a normal loyalty based on
that and that'll LT is to the try
meaning the guy who takes the bullet is
the guy who's most despised disposable
for the tribe at that moment
mmm-hmm the tribe is way bigger than you
and if you're married you're gonna
discover that if you if you die on the
battlefield your wife will be sir
forever celebrating the trial being a
war Widow is the ultimate status among
women he's probably also the future
metric because her husband sacrificed
himself for the tribe okay and all these
dynamics are working within us in the
modern world just on a subliminal sort
sort of level right yeah okay so when
we're not doing military work and we're
not out there fighting for the time
literally we're gonna kill us in the
process the periods in between when the
men do the hunting and the women do the
berry picking in the child-rearing
but when that happens that means the
tribes gonna focus on a story which is
the peacetime story and that's the story
of God God then becomes the ultimate
poor father who looks it doesn't
benevolently but firmly meaning he has
the phallic gaze that that's what we
program to look for all the time look to
the sky to find this smile that looks at
us but at the same time tells us what
reality is like cannot run away from
reality
yeah so tell us what that's what for
fear of God means in the positive sense
yes the fear of destiny the fear of
contingency the fear of surprise the
fear of sudden decease if they were
going mad if I'm eating the wrong plant
the fear of being killed by the animal
you were supposed to kill Oh
all the dangers out there that you're
confronted with every day in your life
are fears of God because destiny self is
God because time is God mm-hmm
now ultimate God is the time axis
contingency and we interpret contingency
as Hagel said we interpret contingency
because it's just unfathomable to us
we interpret that as destiny we look at
it in inside that's exactly what things
become determined to us like they're
meaningful to us like they were supposed
to because when we look at the past to
try to find erection forward because
what meets us in the future is nothing
but a blind merciless contingency and we
can't handle a kiss so defined order in
that chaos and orientate ourselves we go
back and find meaning in our past this
is Hegel's greatest insight if I'm
meaning the past we make the past
meaningful through a story we're
supposed to be here mm-hmm we find
meaning in the past that's great
this is religion this is court in
religion and we haven't left religion no
we're just a bad religion today lousy
religions stupid religion individualism
marketing everybody being alone fighting
each other standing in the gym three
hours a day doing cosmetics and pumping
up muscles to be on tinder at night and
then getting drunk and taking drugs just
to just to sedate ourselves cuz it's so
fucking unbearable the whole thing so in
our first talk you you gave me a
definition of religion can you say that
again
how is eating old french word really god
it's Latin French - meaning what
connects people what connects people no
no no clear phrase right connecting
people that's wisdom there's nothing to
do with gods it's not all with gods
don't you have to have a God in theology
understand that's the knowledge of what
God could be in gods could be that's
called theology you can do poly theology
you can do more of theology we do sin
theology which is the the science or the
philosophical discipline that studies
how gods are created sin the
that's what I do insert this and that's
what I do ask the metaphysis it's just I
study the origin of gods what gods are
and what role they play in our
imagination yes yeah yeah there's I
guess there's non theistic religions and
theistic religions right yeah and
polytheistic and synthesis those people
in the West would just assume that that
all religions need to have a God for
half garlics but yeah at least is an
American perspective in it's just
blatantly untrue
Jainism never had two gods Erasmus never
had to God Buddhism never had a God the
vast majority has never had gods and
mystics never had gods mystics always
think the God which is implanted and
projected they know the testicle
contingency or the real gods that's what
the mystics always knew in ancient Iran
even have their own religion within the
religion which is very clever
so whereas cynicism was essentially like
there's old are that's how things work
that's exist ISM is master that's how we
relate to this existence as a
consciousness can relate to existence to
make decisions we have to go mr.
president Oh doc master that's divinity
okay that's essentially the Holy Spirit
will up the father and the son you're
set you loose elastic then you have Xue
Devon listen inside of that which is the
mystical religion and they worship time
but time to be massive please observe a
general neutral God that doesn't care
about us huh well that can ease the
universe today right you understood the
universe is enormous
well mister the universe doesn't care
about us I understood they'd be very
very very very tiny on a very very small
planet it's not the fact that the
universe doesn't care about us means we
need to care about each other that's not
a corny ID errors oh no no no you did
exactly the right conclusion
sometimes corny ideas are brilliant deep
that means
six is thrown back at us if there is no
external God that cares about us if
there is no phallic gaze out there if
there isn't even a mother earth in a
mother universe while there is one she
doesn't care
mother earth survives without us if we
die then she will give the cockroaches a
million years to then probably make the
same mistake so no the earth doesn't
care about us there's no such thing as a
harmony in nature or anything like that
at all nature is just completely
continued and you can blow up the storm
at any time and kill you
what shot so what we're left with is
humanity we let through the humans we
can relate to 250 of them that's okay
we certainly live in an age we have to
relate to seven billion of them and we
really pray to the machines they can
help us up because if they can't we will
fail and will probably blow ourselves up
with the bombs we create so you think
the machines are gonna save us and in
some sense I don't think we have any
other option I think the machines are
how can the machines save us how could
that happen I don't understand you know
blockchains work not really lock chain
is a technology even though it's energy
consuming and costing it can still
connect with a thousand people in a long
chain for all these thousand people in
that chain are strangers to each other
and still trust each other mm-hmm the
simple version of that is when you get
into an uber car and the uber driver is
driving uber passenger and you both
giving each other grades for your
behavior during that shared experience I
see but the technology is still just the
vehicle no it is it is not the current
products of our technological
interaction you are a byproduct of how
you interact with technology is digital
decides how you think it was the
printing press how that decide how you
think this is Jane Issa Marshall McLuhan
you've read our historical properly you
got it so we are byproducts of our own
interactions between human beings and
between humans and machines okay so I'm
dividing human beings in technology
that's the mistake I made
yeah yeah I mean you and I today here
are incredibly digital humans we would
not survive art and wilderness today we
probably die right away because we had
no idea how hard to survive in that
moment we're completely dependent on the
time and the age of the society we live
in
let's be humble about that let's be
honest about that
meaning the technology is now available
to us when you think about where they're
heading if they are designed in a way to
serve humanity that means we create more
of the blockchain as meaning we create
more tools that make us trust strangers
because we know we're not gonna love the
stranger Jared are living assets are
wrong Critchley is wrong philosophers
had hoped that we could love this
changes there's a bullshit not gonna
happen
does it doesn't start with how we
actually work it doesn't understand the
human psyche mm-hmm and we have to work
from this psyche now what do we do then
well we know that the people who can
collaborate with thousands of other
people can together with those people
create value and far outstrips any value
or you only stay within the community
250 with a fortress built around because
that's no longer an option
they cannot return to the first villages
there is no global village Marshall
McLuhan was wrong there's a global
Empire and a tiny village in our head
they're not compatible unless we quickly
make technologies make them compatible
mm-hmm so the global empires the
internet yeah and we wrote that book 116
years ago it's all there it was coarse
misunderstood if people understood it
they should rocks at us but yeah that's
the kind of work we do we're in this for
the long run well this is for the long
run and I'm in this for the long run and
most stuff I do now will only be
understood 50 100 years ago will you get
it and the guys wrong support customers
and they get it that gives me hope
the more we can spread lease ID ISM and
the more I can get feedback of my deism
and weren't coming even further they're
happier I am that's the whole point with
this conversation
I called the synthetic intelligence
without synthetic intelligence we will
not survive on this planet yeah and it
isn't even climate is the bombs there's
the biggest threat of all yea the bombs
that are just scattered around yeah
we're only generation away from drones
being built with atomic bombs put on
them and you think Islamist is a problem
there gonna be a lot of pissed-off guys
out there try to impress girls the wrong
way it'll be more than happy to sand
bumps on the drones into heavily
populate their isn't just blow people up
as we write about digital ibid oh you're
saying it's probably gonna happen it's
very very likely going to happen it is
nobody's doing anything to prevent it it
is very likely that it will happen an
East dropping and everybody's not gonna
solve the problem so how do we solve the
problem how do we start well you need to
simply not create an environment where
guys are inspired to do that and by
creating large populations of young men
without purpose you create exactly the
vironment the Middle East created with
the wrong economies from the 1950s
forward redirects errand we did the same
thing in Europe in the eighteen hundreds
we had tons of young men but no purpose
again that brings me back to the
importance of Jordan Peterson right
innocence because because he has whole
mission is to give young men I mean it's
not he wants to give you on women
purpose as well but but but that that's
what needs to be done to prevent the
extreme dangers that that we're facing
is the reason why most young men because
young men are are dangerous and the use
of them talk about young men here is
because women are passive aggressive men
are openly aggressive women bitch and
they kill you psychologically whereas
men will go take up arms and kill you
physiologically and we talked about open
violence here which is what you do with
drones and pumps you're not gonna be
able to atomic bombs that spill gossiped
right they will spill atomic shit on you
okay young men young women also have one
advantage here mm-hmm because child
rearing belongs to the inner circuit all
women are born with meaning
purpose even if they don't give birth to
their own children they get a dog and
they become a great aunt and they part
of the child growing process
biologically women are part of the
chattering process whatever they do they
got one benefit with that they have the
purpose problem solved yeah but if the
men don't have it together then the
women are screwed as well aren't they I
mean so women will be blown up by these
bombs and the woman would scream and
they'll be terrified because the horror
starts with paranoia and paranoia is
female trait women are oversensitive
that means learn one thing women are
oversensitive means they're clever and
intelligent too so take their warnings
seriously if the women aren't
comfortable something probably a good
chance to check it out what's going on
maybe there's something to it okay sure
I think I think that's that's like it's
it's very important before you go ahead
and do something to to have a sense of
how the women react to it or feel about
it or there's a form of intelligence
it's a form intuitive intelligence but
but don't let the borderline nutcase
just take over that because they're
gonna go paramon everything okay you
need to let the mature clever woman who
know oh oh they're Talent step forward
and ask them what do you sense they said
there's something wrong with this what
could that be back to the guys for us to
figure out because we're sitting at the
drawing board right so you can use women
that way and you should use women that
way that's where they they're strong the
strong on purpose in the strongly
intuition in that sense so that's a
female intelligence incredibly important
for the tribe then you go to the outer
circuit and that's where the guys have
to come in southern guys don't fill the
bomb and the way you convince the other
guys not to build a bomb is by simply
number one fix our fucking growing up
thick fix their fix their bad
relationships and mother father and and
grown-ups to begin one mm-hmm
if you didn't go through the phallic
intrusion became this boy Pharaoh's full
of themselves and their narcissism as
usual terrorists are by the way you need
to rework their entirety chocolate
mm-hmm
and make them understand that they can
actually contribute creatively to the
tribe instead of from bumps and they'll
be way more loved that way all the
terrible yeah and they just need a
little bit as I guess that Peterson says
they just need a little bit of
encouragement right because they have so
much actual it libidinous energy like
yeah and the one thing you must not do
is to force them to hang out with women
and sit and behave like women be he eat
that can't a young cocky 20 year old guy
say you're gonna sit there with some
other guys and talk about your feelings
no you can't force matriarchy onto young
men they don't get it it's not them yeah
send them out in the forest and asked
him to build something